Good morning.In the last few lectures I've been talking about the history of domestic building construction.
早上好，在过去的几堂课里，我一直在介绍国内房屋构造的历史。
But today I want to begin looking at some contemporary,experimental designs for housing.
但是今天我想介绍一些当代的房屋实验设计。
So,I'm going to start with a house which is constructed more or less under the ground.
所以，我将从或多或少的地下房屋建造开始说起。
And one of the interesting things about this project is that the owners - both professionals but not architects - wanted to be closely involved,
关于这个项目的一件趣事是房主想要密切加入，他们是专业人士但不是建筑师，
so they decided to manage the project themselves.
所以他们打算自己管理这个项目。
Their chief aim was to create somethere that was as environmentally-friendly as possible.
他们的主要目的是把某处建造得尽可能的有益于环境。
But at the same time they wanted to live somewhere peaceful - they'd both grown up in a rural area and disliked urban life.
但是同时，他们想住在宁静的地方，他们都在乡村长大，厌恶城市生活。
So the first thing they did was to look for a site.
所以他们做的第一件事是找地点。
And they found a disused stone quarry in a beautiful area.
他们在一片美丽的地方找到了一个废弃的采石场。
The price was relatively low,and they liked the idea of recycling the land,as it were.
价格相对便宜，他们喜欢再利用这片土地的这个想法。
As it was,the quarry was an ugly blot on the landscape,and it wasn't productive any longer,either.
事实上，这个采石场是这片风景区的败笔，它早就停产了。
They consulted various architects and looked at a number of designs before finally deciding on one.
他们咨询了各类建筑师，看了许多设计后才最终作出决定。
As I've said,it was a design for a sort of underground house,and it was built into the earth itself,with two storeys.
正如我说的，这是设计地下房屋，它建在地里，有两层。
The north,east and west sides were set in the earth,and only the sloping,south-facing side was exposed to light.
北面、东面和西面建在地下，只有朝南的斜坡曝露在阳光之下。
That was made of a double layer of very strong glass.
它由双层强硬的玻璃制成。
There were also photovoltaic tiles fixed to the top and bottom of this sloping wall.
斜壁的顶部和底部还装有光电的瓷砖。
These are tiles that are designed to store energy from the sun.
这些瓷砖用于储存来自太阳的能量。
And the walls had a layer of foam around them too,to increase the insulation.
而且墙的四周还有一层泡沫，用来增强隔热。